[Translated to fr] ...should he have, Colonel?
[Translated to fr] You snotty little bastard.
[Translated to fr] [Ross] Your Honor, I'd like to ask for a recess.
[Translated to fr] I'd like an answer to the question, Judge.
[Translated to fr] The court will wait for an answer.
[Translated to fr] If Lieutenant Kendrick, gave an order...
[Translated to fr] that Santiago wasn't to be touched...
[Translated to fr] ...then why did he have to be transferred?
[Translated to fr] Colonel?
[Translated to fr] Lt. Kendrick ordered the code red, didn't he,
[Translated to fr] because *that's* what you told Lt. Kendrick to do!
[Translated to fr] [Ross] Object!
[Translated to fr] [Kaffee] And when it went bad, you cut these guys loose!
[Translated to fr] [Randolph] That will be all, Counsel.
[Translated to fr] [Ross] Your Honor!
[Translated to fr] [Randolph] Counsel, I'll hold you in contempt!
[Translated to fr] [Kaffee] You had Markinson sign a phony transfer order!
[Translated to fr] [Ross] YOUR HONOR!
[Translated to fr] [Kaffee] You doctored the log book!
[Translated to fr] [Ross] DAMMIT, KAFFEE!
[Translated to fr] [Kaffee] You coerced the doctor! Now I'm asking you!
[Translated to fr] [Randolph] Consider yourself in contempt!
[Translated to fr] COLONEL JESSUP! DID YOU ORDER THE CODE RED?!
[Translated to fr] You don't have to answer that question!
[Translated to fr] I'll answer the question.
[Translated to fr] You want answers?!
[Translated to fr] I think I'm entitled to--
[Translated to fr] [Jessup] *You want answers*?!
[Translated to fr] I WANT THE TRUTH!
[Translated to fr] *You can't handle the truth*!
[Translated to fr] Son, we live in a world that has walls, and those
[Translated to fr] walls have to be guarded by men with guns.
[Translated to fr] Who's gonna do it? You?(!) You, Lt. Weinberg?(!)
[Translated to fr] I have a greater responsibility than you can possibly fathom!
[Translated to fr] You weep for Santiago and you
[Translated to fr] curse the Marines. You have that luxury.
[Translated to fr] You have the luxury of not knowing what I know:
[Translated to fr] That Santiago's death - while tragic - *probably* saved lives!
[Translated to fr] And my existence - while grotesque and
[Translated to fr] incomprehensible to you - *saves lives*!
[Translated to fr] You don't want the truth, because deep down
[Translated to fr] in places you don't talk about at parties...
[Translated to fr] You *want* me on that wall.
[Translated to fr] You *need* me on that wall.
[Translated to fr] We use words like "honor", "code", "loyalty".
[Translated to fr] We use this words as the backbone
[Translated to fr] of a life spent *defending* something.
[Translated to fr] You use them as a punchline!
[Translated to fr] I have neither the time, nor the inclination to explain myself
[Translated to fr] to a man who rises and sleeps under the
[Translated to fr] blanket of the very freedom that I provide
[Translated to fr] and then *questions* the manner in which I provide it!
[Translated to fr] I would rather you just said "thank you", and went on your way.
[Translated to fr] Otherwise, I suggest you pick up a weapon and stand a post.
[Translated to fr] *Either way, I don't give a DAMN
[Translated to fr] what you think you are entitled to*!
[Translated to fr] Did you order the code red?
[Translated to fr] [Jessup] I did the job--
[Translated to fr] DID YOU ORDER THE CODE RED?!
[Translated to fr] *YOU'RE GODDAMN RIGHT I DID*!!