[Translated to fr] [Music]
[Translated to fr] hi my name is Jenny I'm a sophomore and
[Translated to fr] this is for all three of you can you say
[Translated to fr] why America is the greatest country in
[Translated to fr] the
[Translated to fr] world diversity and opportunity Lewis uh
[Translated to fr] freedom and freedom so let's keep it
[Translated to fr] that
[Translated to fr] way
[Translated to fr] well the New York
[Translated to fr] Jets no I'm going to hold you to an
[Translated to fr] answer on that what makes America the
[Translated to fr] greatest country in the
[Translated to fr] world why isica not the greatest country
[Translated to fr] in the world Professor that's my
[Translated to fr] answer you're saying
[Translated to fr] let's talk about fine Sharon the Nea is
[Translated to fr] a loser yeah it accounts for a penny out
[Translated to fr] of our paycheck but he gets to hit you
[Translated to fr] with it anytime he wants it doesn't cost
[Translated to fr] money it costs votes it costs airtime
[Translated to fr] and column inches you know why people
[Translated to fr] don't like liberals because they lose if
[Translated to fr] Liberals are so [ __ ] smart like can
[Translated to fr] they lose so goddamn always hey and with
[Translated to fr] a straight face you're going to tell
[Translated to fr] students that America is so Star
[Translated to fr] Spangled awesome that we're the only
[Translated to fr] ones in the world who have freedom
[Translated to fr] Canada has Freedom Japan has Freedom the
[Translated to fr] UK France Italy Germany Spain Australia
[Translated to fr] Belgium has Freedom so 207 sovereign
[Translated to fr] states in the world like 180 of them
[Translated to fr] have freedom and yeah you uh Sorority
[Translated to fr] Girl just in case you accidentally
[Translated to fr] wander into a voting booth one day
[Translated to fr] there's some things you should know and
[Translated to fr] one of them is there is absolutely no
[Translated to fr] evidence to support the statement that
[Translated to fr] we're the greatest country in the world
[Translated to fr] we're seventh in literacy 27th in math
[Translated to fr] 22nd in science 49th in life expectancy
[Translated to fr] 178th in infant mortality third in
[Translated to fr] median household income number four in
[Translated to fr] labor force and number four in export we
[Translated to fr] lead the world in only three categories
[Translated to fr] number of incarcerated citizens per
[Translated to fr] capita number of adults who believe
[Translated to fr] angels are real and defense spending
[Translated to fr] where we spend more than the next 26
[Translated to fr] countries combined 25 of whom are allies
[Translated to fr] now none of this is the fault of a
[Translated to fr] 20-year-old college student but you
[Translated to fr] nonetheless are without a doubt a member
[Translated to fr] of the worst period generation period
[Translated to fr] ever period so when you ask what makes
[Translated to fr] us the greatest country in the world I
[Translated to fr] don't know what the [ __ ] you're talking
[Translated to fr] about
[Translated to fr] sure used to
[Translated to fr] be we stood up for what was
[Translated to fr] right we fought for moral reasons we
[Translated to fr] passed laws struck down laws for moral
[Translated to fr] reasons we waged Wars on poverty not
[Translated to fr] poor
[Translated to fr] people we sacrificed we cared about our
[Translated to fr] neighbors we put our money where our
[Translated to fr] mouths were and we never beat our chest
[Translated to fr] we built great big things made ungodly
[Translated to fr] technological advances explored the
[Translated to fr] universe cured diseases we cultivated
[Translated to fr] the world's greatest artists and the
[Translated to fr] world's greatest
[Translated to fr] economy we reached for the
[Translated to fr] Stars acted like men we aspired to
[Translated to fr] intelligence we didn't belittle it it
[Translated to fr] didn't make us feel
[Translated to fr] inferior we didn't identify ourselves by
[Translated to fr] who we voted for in the last election
[Translated to fr] and we didn't we didn't scare so easy
[Translated to fr] we were able to be all these things and
[Translated to fr] do all these things because we were
[Translated to fr] informed by great men men who were
[Translated to fr] revered first step in solving any
[Translated to fr] problem is recognizing there is
[Translated to fr] one America is not the greatest country
[Translated to fr] in the world
[Translated to fr] anymore enough